First three minutes are without sound.
首三分钟没有声音
The Left Side - Problems of the Subconscious
潜意识的问题，左脉
May 13th, 1982, Christchurch Hove, Brighton, England
英国布莱顿1982年5月13日
Good conditionings.
我要告诉你，制约也有好的
In the way, in the same way, you can have good habits
同样，你既能有好习惯也能
and bad habits.
有坏习惯
If habits inhibit or
习惯能约束或
obstruct your ascent,
阻碍我们升进
they also can help to stabilize you.
亦能帮助稳定我们
The conditioning comes to you from the matter
制约来自我们每天
with which we are dealing every day.
打交道的物质
When a human being sees the matter, he aggressor it and
当人类看到任何物品，便想侵占它
he wants to use that matter for his own purpose.
想运用这些物品以达致个人的目的
He changes the forms of the matter for his own purpose.
为个人的目的，他改变物质的形态
He starts getting used to matter
开始运用物质以令自己舒适
as comfort, or as a help or a guide in life.
或运用它来帮助自已，指引自己
The more you start depending on matter,
你越依赖物质
the more your spontaneity is finished,
你的自然本性就越快完蛋
because you’re dealing with the dead.
因为你在处理死物
Matter, when it is dead, then only we deal with it.
物质，当它是死的，我们才去处理它
When it is living we are not so much bothered about it.
但当它仍是活的，我们却不大在意它
So the deadness of that matter settles within us when
当我们为着个人的目来运用物质
we start using that matter for our purpose.
这些死物便会在我们内里安顿下来
But how are we to otherwise exist? Is the question
若不是这样，我们怎能生存？
people can ask. If God has given us this material things
这是人们会问的问题。若神赐予我们这些物质
and this matter to be used,
让我们能运用它们
are we not supposed to use them?
我们是否不应运用它们
And are we not supposed to enjoy them?
不应享用它们？
But we don’t enjoy. We …
我们却不享受。我们…
before Realization you cannot enjoy any matter.
在得到自觉前，你不能享受任何物质
You can only form a habit and may become
你只是养成了习惯
a slave of that matter, before Realization.
或许成为物质的奴隶，在得到自觉前
It’s a principle of, fundamental principle of economics
这是原则…经济学的原则是
that wants in general are never satiable.
需求一般是永远得不到满足
Means today you want to buy something like a carpet.
意思是今天你想买一块地毯
All right, you bought it.
好，买吧
So now that carpet becames a headache, because it’s
这块地毯却让你感到头痛，因为
your possession, you have to look after it.
你拥有它，便要照顾它
You have to insure it, you have to worry about it that it
要为它购买保险，你要先忧心它
doesn’t get spoiled, first of all.
不会被弄脏
And secondly you really get
其二，你想再购买
into another mood of buying something else.
其他物品
Now you have bought the carpet, finished.
你已经买了地毯，就这样
Then you have to have something else, then you have to
你要买其他物品
then you have to have something else.
你再想要其他物品
So it does not satiate you; it does not give you the joy.
你的要求是没法得到满足，也没法带给你喜乐
Matter can never give you joy.
物质永远没法带给你喜乐
It’s the Spirit that gives you joy.
只有灵才能给你喜乐
And when the ascent takes place,
当你升进
when you become the Spirit, then matter takes another
当你成为灵，你对物质的价值
value system within ourselves,
便有另一种看法
the value system of matter is very different.
你对物质的价值观会截然不同
As I’m sure Jason must have told you that
我肯定积臣必定有告诉你
when you get your Realization,
当你得到自觉
then you start feeling the Cool Breeze in the hand.
你的双手开始感到有凉风
In relationship to matter
至于物质
it’s very helpful to be a realized soul,
成为灵是大有帮助
because immediately you know
因为你马上知道
what is good for you and what is bad for you.
什么对你好什么对你坏
For example, you eat something that’s not good for you.
例如，你吃了一些对你不好的食物
Immediately you’ll lose your vibrations
便马上失去生命能量
and will become hot.
变得很热
Even looking at it, it may happen.
即使只是看着这些食物，或许也有这种感觉
You want to sit on a chair on which somebody who is a
当你坐在一个很差的人
very wrong type of a person has sat,
坐过的椅子
immediately you’ll feel, “Oh, something wrong
你马上感到︰「噢，这里
in this place.” With your vibrations,
有些不对劲。」
which is a definite thing, an absolute thing.
生命能量是明确的、绝对的
And this conditioning can only be over –
这种制约只会在…
these habits can be overcome only if you become the Spirit,
这些习惯只会在你成为灵后才能克服
because Spirit is always dominated by the matter.
因为灵常常受物质控制
And the Spirit has to overcome that domination of the matter.
灵必须克服物质的控制
Actually, Spirit cannot be dominated by anything.
事实上，灵不会受任何事物控制
But what I mean is that it is covered, like the sun can be
我是说它被遮蔽，就如浮云
covered with clouds.
遮蔽着太阳
In the same way all our domination,
同样，所有支配我们的
or we can say all our enslavement of the matter,
又或我们可以说，物质对我们的奴役
makes us dominate our Spirit in the sense that
令我们控制我们的灵，某种意义而言
we cover it up. The clouds are there,
我们把灵遮蔽。浮云仍在
we can’t see the Spirit. We can’t feel It.
令我们看不见灵，感觉不到灵
The spontaneity which is the beauty of the Spirit
灵的美在于自然而然
we do not feel, in a person.
我们感觉不到，感觉不到别人
So, in judging a person, what do we judge?
在评价别人时，我们在评价些什么？
How that person looks, what dress he’s wearing,
这人外表怎么样，他穿什么衣服
how he walks. What are his formal ways,
他怎样走路，他通常的言行举止
does he know how to say “Thank you”, “Sorry” or not.
他懂不懂说︰「谢谢」，「对不起」
You see? All these things impress us very much.
你明白吗？所有这些都令我们留下印象
What sort of a car he has, what sort of a house he has.
他拥有怎样类型的车，你有怎样的房子
Maybe we may miss, we may miss a saint.
或许我们错过了，错过了一个圣人
We may miss Christ again
我们或许再次错过基督
because He was a carpenter’s son.
只因他是木匠的儿子
How are we to know who is Christ?
我们怎知道谁是基督？
Is there any way of finding out who is Christ?
有什么途径方法让我们知道谁是基督？
Many people are now talking “Christ is going to come,
现在很多人说︰「基督会来
He’s going to come on the television.”
他会上电视。」
You can put up anyone there as Christ.
你可以把任何人放在那位置而视他为基督
How are we going to make it out?
我们怎能分辨？
By His dress or by some sort of a thing they have done?
凭他的衣着，或他做的任何事情
Most of the paintings of Christ and most of His statues
大部分我见过的基督的画像或雕像
that I’ve seen are no where near Christ,
都完全不像基督
no where near Christ, you see.
完全不像，你要明白
They are horrid things. I don’t know what are they.
他们很可怕，我不知道他们是谁
So how will you make it out that this is Christ or not?
你怎能分辨出谁是基督？
Or this is some sort of a hokus pokus fellow or some sort
又或这只是某些懂戏法的家伙
of a person who has come just deliberately to delude us
或是某些故意哄骗我们
from reality.
远离实相的家伙
There is no way out, to find out
没有任何途径方法能找出真相
what is the truth because we are so much used to material
因为我们已经习惯只着眼于物质的
forms that we have.
表面的形态
For example, our idea of art also is in the same way
就如我们对艺术的概念也是
molded.
像模子一样
We like this kind of art.
我们喜欢这种艺术
If you ask them, “Why?”
若你问他们︰「为什么？」
“Because, you know, this has this kind of a thing
「因为，你也知道
– harmony” Or maybe,
这种东西是，很和谐。」
“this is more proportioned” and all that.
又或许「这是比较合比例。」就是这样
But how do you know?”
「你怎知道？」
You know because you’ve read certain books or maybe
你知道是因为你读了一些书籍，又或你
that you have understood from somebody else
从某人身上学懂
that this is art, this is beautiful. I mean, you brand
「这是艺术」，「这很美」我是说你标签
something as beautiful, but is it really?
某些东西为美，它真的美吗？
If it is beauty, it should be Spirit, because
若它是美的，那必定是灵，因为
Spirit is beauty and beauty is Spirit.
灵是美，美亦是灵
So is it, is it beauty? How do you make out
所以它是，它美丽吗？你怎能分辨出
that this art is beautiful or not?
这艺术是否美丽？
For example, according to all normal ideas of
就如若按照一般人对
womanhood, I don’t think
女性的看法，我不认为
Mona Lisa is a beautiful woman.
蒙娜丽莎是个美丽的女性
I mean, these days you see mosquito-like women are
我的意思是今天像蚊子般的妇女
regarded as beautiful.
被视为美丽
So how they call Mona Lisa so beautiful?
他们怎能说蒙娜丽莎很美丽？
What’s going on?
她拥有什么？
Thousands of people would be assembled to see that
成千上万的人聚集一起去看
painting. Why? What is that?
她的油画，为什么，为什么会这样？
Only vibrations will tell you that it emits vibrations.
只有生命能量能给你答案，它散发生命能量
It appeals to your Spirit without your knowledge.
在你不知情下，它吸引感染你的灵
You’re not aware of it. It appeals to your Spirit.
你毫不察觉，它吸引你的灵
That’s why universally that painting is appreciated.
这就是为何这帧油画处处都受到赞赏
But when this conditioning becomes collective,
当这种制约变成集体的制约
any such conditioning becomes collective and you
任何制约成为集体的制约
accept, “This is the form that is beauty; this is the form
你都会接受。「这种形态是美丽
that is reality; this is the form that is spontaneity”,
这种形态是实相，这种形态是自然而然。」
then the confusion starts.
混乱因此产生
The confusion starts at that point,
当它变成集体的事情
when it becomes a collective thing.
混乱便会产生
For example I met some people of some gurus.
例如我遇见一些人的一些导师
And I asked them,
我问他们︰
“What makes you think that your guru is truthful,
「你怎么知道你的导师是真的
what has he given you?
他给了你什么？」
He said, “because sitting in my chair I just start jumping
他说︰「因为我坐在椅子上，便开始抖动
by myself. I don’t do it but it happens, it’s spontaneous.”
我不是故意的，是自然的发生。」
And in my presence, the way his body was moving was
当我在场，他的身体在抖动
so horrifying.
很吓人
Anybody would have tremendous compassion
任何人都会
and concern for such a person,
对这个不能安坐五分钟的人
that you can’t sit for five minutes straight …
有极大的慈悲和关注…
A woman in the audience says: Excuse me, it wasn’t
一个女听众︰「很抱歉
spontaneous, it was nerve …
这不是自然而然，是神经质。」…
Yes, that’s what I’m saying …
「对，我正要这样说…」
Woman: You’re wrong in what You talk.
女士︰「你说错了。」
What?
「说错什么？」
Woman: About everything
女士︰「全都说错。」
From where do you come?
「你哪里来？」
Woman: Up the road.
女士︰「在路上。」
That’s it. Better go.
「就这样，最好走吧！」
Woman: Don’t worry. I am.
女士︰「不用担心，我要离开这里。」
Look at that. She’ll go to the pub now.
「看看，她现在到酒吧。」
Must try to understand the subtleties, you see?
你们要尝试明白这个精微层面，明白吗？
If you are confirmed it what.
若你对它确定
Now supposing somebody starts jumping in the thing.
现在例如有人开始武断的说一些事情
As she says it’s true – nerves.
就如若她说的是真的 – 神经质
That means you’re not in control of your nerves, isn’t it?
意思是你控制不了你的神经，对吗？
Don’t you think so? You’re not in control.
你认为是这样吗？你不受控制
You have not controlled.
你不受控制
Spontaneity is a thing which is not the thing that makes
自然而然不会令你
you a slave.
成为奴隶
This is the point I’m trying to bring.
我要说的就是这一点
It doesn’t; it makes you a master.
它不会奴役你，它只会令你成为主人
Spontaneity must make you a master
自然而然要能令你成为主人
and not a slave of anything.
而不是奴隶
She must have come from TM because TM people
她必定是来自超觉静坐，因为练习超觉静坐的人
jump like that.
就像这样抖动
And they end up as epileptic people.
最终他们都会染上癫痫症
I have cured so many of them.
我曾经治好很多这样的人
I don’t know if someone has come from there.
我不知道有谁来自哪里
Even the head of their academy in Scotland who –
即使是他们在苏格兰学院的主管
flying squad academy, as I call it,
他是---我叫它作飞行队学校---
where people pay three thousand – now this gentleman
人们要付三千元。这个坐在这里的男士
sitting here is one of them who suffered.
是受害者之一
When they suffer then they know what it is.
当他们受苦，便知道那是什么一回事
The other day we saw somebody with epilepsy of such
几天前我们看到有人癫痫症发作
frequency. The poor child, he was hardly twenty-six
次数很频密，可怜的孩子，他还不到二十六岁
years of age, young man, supposed to enjoy his life,
年青人，理应享受人生
was going into such trauma, you can’t imagine.
却走进这种困境，你不能想象
And if this is happening to somebody going to a guru,
若这种事情是发生在某个想成为导师的人身上
you paid for it,
变成这样还要付钱
how can it be anywhere near Spirit?
这又怎会是与灵接近？
This is what I’m trying to tell you, that
我想告诉你们
Spirit gives you spontaneity in which you are the master.
灵给你自然而然，你是导师
You are the master of yourself, complete master,
自己的导师，完全的导师
no enslavement of any kind, no habits formation coming.
没有任何奴役，没有养成任何习惯
All habits drop out.
所有习惯都戒掉
You become so, so spontaneous that I don’t have to tell you.
你变得那么自然而然，我不需要告诉你
You just drop out all habits and you become a
你自会戒掉所有习惯
master of your self.
变成自己的导师
That should happen to you.
这应会在你身上发生
Instead of that, if you indulge into things which enslave
但取而代之，若你沉迷于
you, you will like it for awhile
奴役你的事情，你可能会喜欢它一会儿
because you can’t help it.
因为你抗拒不了它
But, if you really sit down you will know that it’s not the
但若你真的坐下想想，便会知道
thing that you wanted.
这不是你想要的
You wanted to be the master of your self.
你想要的是成为自己的导师
Now here in this map as we show we have two powers,
就如这能量图显示，我们有两个力量
left and right powers.
左和右的力量
The left power is the power that gives us conditioning –
左脉的力量是给我们制约
left side, the subconscious, the collective subconscious.
左边，潜意识，集体潜意识
That gives us the conditioning.
它给我们制约
Now, if you try to deny all that, then the right side is
若你想否定所有这些，右边
even worse.
甚至更差
It gives us action, but with action we can become very
它给我们行动，但行动令我们变得
ego oriented.
自我中心
So both ways it can be troublesome.
所以二者都可以令人很烦恼
Supposing you say that “All right, I’ll have no
就如你说︰「好吧，我没有
conditioning from anytime. What’s wrong in doing this?
任何制约，这样做有什么错
What’s wrong in doing that?”
那样做有什么错？」
And if you just move with that idea, with that freedom,
若你有这种想法，这种自由
it will be abandonment, it may not be freedom.
这是放任，或许这不是自由
Because freedom must have wisdom behind it.
因为自由背后要有智慧
So both the sides,
因此这两边
the movements on both the sides are wrong.
往左走或往右走都是错的
So what is all right?
那么什么是对？
In the center is not to get conditioned by anything and
就是在中央，既不受制约束缚
not to be ego oriented.
又不自我中心
But how to do it is the problem.
怎能做到是个大问题
The problem is how to do it.
问题出于怎能做到
To be spontaneous is to be absolutely free.
要自然而然就是要绝对自由
Now I would consider these two powers as, say, a brake
我认为这两个力量，就如车辆的煞车掣
and an accelerator in a car.
和加速器
Now you use both the powers.
你运用这两个力量
You use the brake first, you use the accelerator.
先用煞车掣，再用加速器
You try to control these two powers.
你想控制这两个力量
But, first of all it is difficult to understand
开始时要懂怎样运用控制
how you can use these powers.
这两个力量是很困难的
Gradually, with practice you’ll do it.
透过练习，你便渐渐学懂
You know how to drive the car,
你知道怎样驾车
you become the good driver.
成为好司机
After becoming the good driver, still
成为好司机后，你仍不是
you are not the master of the driving,
驾车师傅
but then you become the master.
接下来你才成为师傅
So, today the master within us, within us is the Spirit.
今天你们内在的导师，内在的导师是灵
But before Realization, you are not the master
在得到自觉前，你不是导师
because the master has not come in our conscious mind.
因为我们仍未有作为导师的意识
It is not expressing in our conscious mind.
它仍未表达在我们的意识里
In the sense that we are not empowered by Its powers.
某程度上我们仍未获这些力量的授权
The Spirit exists; It has Its own powers.
灵存在着，它有自己的力量
But we haven’t felt those powers within us.
我们内在仍未感到这些力量
Once we feel the powers of the Spirit,
一旦我们感觉到灵的力量
we are empowered by our own powers which are there.
我们便获自己的力量授权，它就在这里
The powers are within us.
在我们内里
These are our own powers.
这是我们自己的力量
We don’t have to borrow from anyone, ask from anyone,
我们不用向别人借用，不用向别人要求
they are in ourselves.
它们就在我们内里
The Spirit is within us –
灵在我们内里
only thing that Spirit has to bring light in our,
唯一是灵要把光带进
in our consciousness.
我们的意识
It has to come in our consciousness.
它要进入我们的意识
In simple medical terminology we can see, say that the
以简单的医学词汇，我们能看到，例如
Spirit must manifest Itself in our central nervous system,
灵必须在我们的中枢神经系统彰显
in our central nervous system so that we should know
在我们的中枢神经系统，因此我们应该知道
what we are doing.
我们该做什么
Not that we start just jumping on the chair, or some
不是在椅子上跳跃，又或
people said, “Oh you, we just start doing it.”
有些人说︰「噢，你，我们开始这样做。」
It is hypnosis.
这是催眠状态
It’s not correct. You’re not in conscious mind.
是不对的，你是没有意识的
You are doing it out of hypnosis.
你这样做是因为被催眠
Hypnosis may be coming from outside force.
催眠可能来自外在的力量
It’s not your force, your awareness,
不是你的力量，不是你的知觉
your understanding, your power.
你的理解，你的力量
It is somebody else’s because you’re not doing it.
是其他人，因为不是你做的
As matter has a power to overpower us, in the same way
因为物质有力量控制我们，同样
there are some material things, I should say, which are
我必须要说，有些物质
very dangerous, which are placed.
是被视为很危险的
For example now cancer, take cancer,
例如癌症，以癌症为例
cancer overpowers.
癌症控制我们
It’s a very serious thing.
这是很严重危急的东西
Cancer overpowers you; you cannot overpower cancer.
癌症控制我们，我们却不能控制癌症
Take a very concrete example.
举一个实例
Now how is it caused?
癌是如何引致的？
Doctors say this way, that way.
医生说︰「这样，那样。」
We, Sahaja Yoga can cure cancer, definitely a hundred
我们…霎哈嘉瑜伽能治好癌症，肯定的百分百能把它治好
percent it can cure, it has cured.
亦已把它治好
Many Sahaj Yogis have cured cancer.
很多霎哈嘉瑜伽士已经把癌治好
How? Is very simple.
怎样治好？很简单
That you become master of yourself and you master the
就是你变成自己的导师，你掌握
disease also,
这个疾病
you master everything.
也能掌握一切
Because the master is within you,
因为导师就在你内里
it has not come in your conscious mind is the only link is
但它仍未进入你的意识，唯一的联系仍未连上
left, and when that happens Yoga takes place,
一旦连上了，瑜伽便会发生
union takes place.
合一也会发生
We should now completely keep ourselves limited to
我们现在要完全把注意力
Self Realization, about God I’ll tell next time.
放在自觉上，我下次再告诉你关于神
Self-Realization means to bring your Spirit
自觉的意思是把你的灵
into your conscious mind.
带进你的意识
Now how cancer is caused? Let’s see here what happens.
什么引致癌症？让我们看看这里什么发生？
It is caused by left-sided activity.
它是由左边活动所引发的
Now left sided activities are emotional traumas,
左边活动是指︰情感的困局
emotional problems, emotional upheavals,
情绪的问题，情绪的波动
emotional insecurities – any kind of insecurity can take
情感的不安全感，任何一种不安全感都能把你
you to the left side.
带往左边
Little more movement can be these horrible gurus
这些可怕的导师只要一点点的举动
because they hypnotize you.
因为他们催眠你
They put you to the left.
便能把你带进左边
They put some spirit in you or I don’t know what they do,
把亡灵附在你身上，我也不知道他们做了些什么
but they put you to the left.
他们把你带往左边
Any one of these activities which are not authorized by
任何不获神授权的活动
God, taken to, you go to the left side,
也会带你到左边
because you cannot ascend in the center.
因为你不能在中央升进
So either you go to the left or to the right.
因此你一是走向左，一是走向右
When you overdo these things, like black magic - you
当你过分做这些事情，像巫术，我听说
have another thing here I’ve heard,
你有另一样东西在这里
some sort of a organization had, and the fellow you see
某些组织，有些家伙
he used to, everything he saw moving in the house.
惯于看到房子里的一切东西都在移动
He came to Sahaj Yoga and his water jug was moving
他来霎哈嘉瑜伽，他的水壶在动
there and this was moving there and he couldn’t explain
这个在移动，他不能解释有什么发生
what was happening in his room.
在他的房间里
He was sitting down and he found something moving
他坐下，发现某些东西
from here to here. It happens.
从这里移到那里，实实在在的在发生
What is that? What is that doing this kind of a thing
这是什么？是谁在做着这种
which you cannot control.
你不能控制的事情？
Again we come to the same point –
我们再次来到同一点
something you cannot control.
一些你不能控制的事情
So you enter into the realm, into the realm
你进入了某个领域
where you are controlled and you are not under your own
进入了你受人控制的领域，一切都
control and that realm, when you enter in,
不在你的控制，这个领域，当你进入
I have always seen all the cancer patients
我常常看到癌症病人
are the ones affected by this.
都是受它影响
Most of them. They’re not aware;
他们大部分人都受它影响。他们意识不到
they do not know how they get into it.
他们不知道自己是怎会进入
For a lady, supposing, say she’s suffering from an
就如对女士来说
insecurity about her husband or maybe something, or
她对丈夫感到不安全，或许是某些事情
maybe she thinks that her husband may leave her any time.
或许她以为丈夫随时会离开她
She loves him. Whatever it is,
她爱他，不管如何
such a woman might get a breast cancer,
这个女人或许会得乳癌
because the insecurities set in, in one of the centers there
因为不安全感已经进入了其中一个轮穴
which you can see here, the center of the Heart -
你可以在这里看到，心轮
Center heart, as we call it.
我们称它为心轮中部
Now if this center goes out of order,
若这个轮穴有故障
if a woman feels insecure for anything whatsoever,
若妇女对任何事都感到不安全
she’s capable – she’s vulnerable to be attacked and she
她有可能…她很易受侵袭
can get into cancer.
便会生癌
So we have to understand life in totality,
所以我们必须整体的去理解生命
and not in one way.
不是单一的
The total impact of life, the total effect of life,
我们必须明白生命的整体作用，人生的整体影响
the total relationship with life must be understood.
生命的整体关系
Now no doctor knows this.
现在没有医生懂这些
Will he know, when he treats the patient for, say,
他懂吗，当他为病人治疗
breast cancer will he know that this lady is insecure?
比如乳癌，他知道这个女士没有安全感吗？
There’s another disease – anorexia –
另一种疾病是厌食症
many girls suffer from it.
很多女孩也受这种病之苦
They don’t just eat. They just give up eating.
他们只是不吃，放弃进食
Now, you do not know why it happens.
你不知道怎会这样
Doctors can’t cure it; nobody can cure it.
医生治不好这个病，没有人能治好它
What is the reason?
什么原因？
The relationship of a girl, of a daughter with the father.
女孩，女儿与父亲的关系
Say father dies and the daughter doesn’t see the father,
例如父亲过世，女儿再也见不到父亲
or in heart she loves the father but she doesn’t express it,
又或女儿很爱她的父亲，但却没有表达出来
or there’s some bad relationship that comes between the
又或
father and the daughter,
父女的关系很差
you get this trouble – anorexia.
女儿便有这个毛病，厌食症
You’ll be amazed but it is impossible for doctors to get –
你会很惊叹，但医生是没法把这病治好
we have some doctors sitting here –
这里也有几位医生
it is impossible for any medical science to go near it.
医学是没法了解这个病
Because we do not see a human being in its totality.
因为我们并非以整体来看人类
It’s a very delicate instrument God has created.
人类是神创造很精巧的器具
The way we are harsh with others,
我们对别人苛刻
the way we sometimes try to trouble others,
麻烦别人
try to make others feel insecured or unfair, unjust.
令别人感到不安全，或对人不公平，不公义
Without our knowledge we really give them
在我们不知情下
a tremendous insecurity, and such insecurities can
我们真的给了他们巨大的不安全感，这种不安全感
work out incurable diseases of which we are not aware.
真的在我们意识不到下令别人染上不治之症
So to understand the totality, what should happen to us?
要明白整体，什么要发生在我们身上？
We should achieve that state where we can see
我们要到达
the totality.
能看到整体的层次
Like if I have to see now, for example, the whole of
就像若我想看…比如想看
Brighton, what should I do?
布莱顿的全貌，我该怎样做？
I should go on a plane and see it from that height.
我要坐上飞机从高处看
I can see the whole. In the same way in your awareness,
便能看到整个布莱顿。同样在你的意识里
in your understanding, you should rise to that point from
在你的理解里，你要升到你能看到
where you can see the whole.
整体的位置
If you cannot see the whole, the partial vision, or we can
若你看不到整体，只看到部分境像，或我们
say, a little that you see can create confusion,
可以说只看到很小部分，你看到的能制造混乱
can create problems and some of them could be of a
制造问题，它们有些的性质是
very, very serious nature.
非常，非常严重
Because as human beings, we do not know what are we.
因为作为人类，我们不知道自己是谁
This is the greatest problem of human beings,
人类最大的问题是
that they’ll say, “I don’t like it.”
他们会说︰「我不喜欢它」。
Now which one is this “I”? Is that your Spirit, or is that
这个「我」是谁？是你的灵或
your ego?
是你的自我？
What is the part that is not liking it?
你不喜欢那一部分？
Or is it your conditioning, because you’re brought up in a
又或是你的制约。因为是以
particular way so you don’t like this?
特别的方式把你养育成人，你因此不喜欢这些？
Which part of you is not liking it?
你的哪一部分不喜欢它？
And you’d be amazed that it is not your Spirit because if
你会感到很惊讶，不是你的灵，因为
Spirit likes, how will you know?
若灵喜欢，你又怎能知道？
It’s only through your vibrations.
它只能透过你的生命能量来知道
When you can feel the vibrations, then only you will say,
当你感到生命能量，那么你才能说︰
“Yes, my Spirit likes it”,
「是，我的灵喜欢它。」
because the vibrations have emitted.
因为生命能量在散发
So we are still in a transition state as human beings.
作为人类，我们仍处于过渡阶段
We have not achieved that state which is called as the
我们仍未到达被称为
state of Self-Realization where you become the Spirit -
自觉的阶段，自觉是我们变成灵
the becoming is the point.
「变成」是重点
Where you become the Spirit you know what you like.
一旦你成为灵，你便知道自己喜欢什么
You really know what you really like,
你真的知道自己喜欢什么
because you are now the reality,
因为你就是实相
you are not any conditioning,
你不是任何制约
you are no more an ego, but you are what you are really,
不再是自我，你是你本来真正的模样
and that is your Spirit.
就是你是灵
And, surprisingly this Spirit is a collective being.
很令人惊讶，灵是集体的存在体
Is no artificial collectivity within us.
我们内在没有表面虚假的集体特征
That also “All right, we belong to all Brighton so we are
也不是︰「好吧，我们属于布莱顿，所以我们是一体。」
one” or “We belong to one street so we are one.”
或「我们属于同一条街，所以我们是一体。」
It’s not like that, but is something that you are,
不是这样，而是某种你是…
absolutely you are a collective being,
你绝对是集体的存在体
and you start feeling that collectivity within you
透过不同能量中心的运作成就
with these different centers working it out.
你开始感觉你内在的集体
And you can feel it - others,
你能感觉到它…别人
you can feel others on your finger tips.
你能在指尖感觉到别人
Can you believe?
你能相信吗？
In the Bible it’s written that your hands will speak.
圣经有写下︰「你的双手会说话。」
The description of these days is that your hands will speak.
这些日子的描述是︰「你的双手会说话。」
Why not people go and find out how does it happen?
人们为什么不去找出什么发生了？
How can your hands speak?
你的双手怎会说话？
This is what happens that on your finger tips you start
发生的是你开始从指尖
feeling and understanding what is reality,
感觉和理解什么是实相
what is beauty, what is joy, what is love.
什么是美，什么是喜乐，什么是爱
This is the left side
这是我们取得的左边
which we get, and ultimately with this left side problems
最终左边的问题令我们
we get physical pain.
肉身感到痛楚
It’s very painful to have left sided problems –
左边有问题是非常痛的
it’s very, very painful.
非常，非常痛的
The pain cannot be explained, no one can understand,
这种痛楚不能向人解释，没有人能明白
nobody can cure it, you can’t tell anyone
没有人能治好它，你不能告诉任何人
and people think that you are fussing, they give you
人们以为你大惊小怪
psychological treatment, you just don’t understand
他们以心理学来医治你，你只是不明白
why this pain is within you.
为什么你有这种痛楚
And this pain comes to you from left side,
这种痛楚来自左边
the subconscious.
来自潜意识
But beyond the subconscious is the collective
超越潜意识是集体
subconscious,
潜意识
and this collective subconscious is the one where
集体潜意识包含一切
whatever is created from the beginning up to today
自创造以来直至今天
in the creation is within. And once you go to the
所创造的东西。一旦你进入
subconscious, you just get lost there.
潜意识，便会迷失
You are so overpowered by this power of subconscious
潜意识的力量控制你
that it is beyond you to understand it,
它是超越你的理解
beyond you to get out of it and beyond you to –
超越你能摆脱它，超越你去…
not to succumb to it.
不是屈服于它
And it goes on increasing.
而它却不断增长
Like I asked some people,
就如我问一些人︰
“Why did you go on doing it when you knew that you
「为什么你知道
were not doing it, somebody else was doing it?
不是你做的，是其他人做的
Still why did you continue to do it?”
但你却仍不停继续这样做？」
They said, “Mother, we were under the blanket,
他们说︰「母亲，我们在毛毯下
it was darkness, we didn’t know where we were moving
完全黑暗，我们不知道自己在哪里移动
and were just going on and on and on.”
所以只能不停的继续下去。」
And as I told you last time, feeling guilty is the biggest
就如我上次告诉你，感到内疚是
blockade.
最大的障碍
Is the biggest blockade because once you start feeling
是最大的障碍因为一旦你
guilty that this center on the left gets blocked and the –
感到内疚，这个轮穴的左边便会有阻塞，而它是…
it’s very difficult.
很困难的
And you don’t know why you are feeling guilty.
你不知道自己为何感到内疚
All the time you’re feeling guilty but you don’t know
你每时每刻都感到内疚，却不知道
why you’re feeling guilty, why these ideas of guilt are
自己为何内疚，为何有这种内疚的想法
coming to you, that this feeling of guilt keeps you away
这种内疚令你远离
from joy, from enjoying anything, from being
喜乐，令你什么也不能享受
spontaneous.
令你不能自然而然
Why? And this explains why we sometimes are
为什么？这解释为何我们有时会不为何事
miserable for nothing at all.
而感到悲哀
Actually, God has not created us to be miserable.
事实上，神并没有创造我们悲哀
He has made us so beautifully, so carefully.
他创造得我们那么美丽，那么小心
He has created us with such love and compassion,
他以爱心和慈悲创造我们
not to make us feel miserable, not for anything.
不是要我们不为什么而悲伤
He doesn’t give us any diseases, no problems.
他没有给我们任何疾病，任何问题
But we have done these things to ourselves by going to
但我们却走向
extremes on the left or the right.
极端的左或极端的右
As I am today talking about only on the left,
因为我今天只谈左边
I would say that to feel miserable for nothing at all is
我要说不为什么而感到悲哀
also wrong, is being unjust to yourself.
也是错的，对你自己也不公平
The people who are left sided must know that they are
偏左脉的人必须知道
the Spirit, that they are that beauty which has to come,
他们是灵，他们是那种要显现
which has to express itself.
要表达出来的美丽
That they are not the people who have to suffer
他们不是每时每刻都受苦
all the time and to live like miserable people.
活得悲哀的人
They are not.
他们不是
But because they take so much upon themselves,
但因为他们承担太多
bear so much upon themselves, they become like that.
忍受太多，令他们变成这样
And to avoid that bearing up they may take to some other
为避免承担忍受，他们或许要养成
habits, you see. Many people take to alcohol
其他习惯，你要明白，很多人酗酒
also for reason because they can’t bear the pangs of life,
是因为他们不能忍受人生的苦楚
they can’t bear it. That’s why they take to it …
他们忍受不了，所以他们酗酒…
but once the Spirit is awakened within you,
一旦你内里的灵被唤醒
you become so strong. You become so joyous,
你便变得那么强，那么喜乐
so spontaneous that all these things drop out,
那么自然而然，你会戒掉所有坏习惯
all those things – so-called diseases, so-called habits -
所有所谓的疾病，所谓的习惯
just drop out
都会退去
and you become a new, blooming personality.
你的品格变得璀璨繁盛
Now the basics of having this center within you –
你内在有这个轮穴的基础
you can blame God for that, “Why did He give us these
你可以为此责备神︰「为何他要
centers on the left hand side, what was the need?
在我们的左边给我们这个能量中心？有何需要？
He should not have given these left sided ones, so we
他不应给我们这个左边的能量中心，那么
would have been just in the center to go.”
我们便能只处于中央。」
But the trouble is the human beings have to know
问题出在人类必须知道
in their own freedom, how to deal with themselves.
他们有自由去处理应对自己
They have to learn little hard way the wisdom.
他们要努力学习智慧
They have to learn by going to extremes
学懂偏向极端
they have suffered. They have to realize it
便会受苦，也必须意识到
because if they have to become truly, absolutely free
若他们变得真诚，拥有完全的自由
they have to rise in their wisdom.
他们必须在智慧里升进
If they’re not wise people, then they cannot enter into the
没有智慧，便不能
Kingdom of God, because they’ll be abandoned people.
进天国，因为他们会被遗弃
Say, people who are abandoned, who don’t understand
就如有些人被遗弃，他们不懂
any laws or regulations, if you get them in England,
任何法律和规则。若你带他们来英国
we’ll have to put them in jail.
我们便要送他们进监狱
In the same way, human beings who have not got that
同样，人类若
wisdom within themselves –
没有智慧---
through sufferings only one learns, but we should not ask
虽然受苦令人学懂，但我们不应
for suffering. When we ask for sufferings, we are asking
要求受苦。当我们要求受苦，实际上
actually for mistakes to begin with.
是要求错误
How will you suffer if you do not commit mistakes?
若你没有犯错，又怎会受苦？
So, when we ask for sufferings we are committing
所以当你要求受苦
mistakes.
实际上你是在犯错
So what we should ask for is nothing but our Spirit,
我们唯一要求的应是我们的灵
and if you ask for your Spirit,
你要求你的灵
it is your own and you have to get it.
它是你自己的，你要得到它
It is in your own right that you’re going to get it.
得到它是你的权利
It’s no way that I’m obliging you or doing something
我不能强迫你，或为你做些
special for you. It’s all there.
特别的事情，它就在这里
You are like a light which is just to be enlightened
你像光，要被点亮的光
because I’m an enlightened light and you become an
因为我是已点亮的光，所以你
enlightened light, you can enlighten other lights also.
变成已点亮的光，你也能点亮其他光
It’s very simple.
就是这样简单
If you become an enlightened light,
若你成为点亮的光
you can enlighten others.
便能点亮其他光
You don’t have to bother about anything else then.
你不用在意什么
You become an enlightened light yourself, that’s the point.
你自己要成为已点亮的光，这是重点
It is all there, it is all your own, you have to just have it.
它全在这里，是你自己的，你只要取得它
It is as simple as that, there is nothing very complicated
就是这样简单，不像这些人那样弄得那么复杂
as these people make it or anything that these
又或是哲学家
philosophers have put before you, nothing of the kind.
放在你面前的东西，不是这样
It’s very simple, it is within you, it is spontaneous,
它是非常简单，在你内里，自然而然
it is a living process as in living process you have
是活生生的生命过程，生命的过程
become human beings,
令你成为人类
you are going to become super human beings.
你要成为超人类
It’s absolutely spontaneous, you can’t pay for it.
这绝对是自然而然的，你不能付钱购买它
How can you pay? I mean, absurd it is!
你又怎能付钱？我是说这是绝对荒谬荒唐！
If it is a living process, how can you pay?
若它是个活生生的生命过程，你又怎能付钱？
How much do you pay to the tree to grow up?
你付了多少钱给树木生长？
I mean in anything living, do we pay anything?
我是说任何活生生的东西，你要付钱吗？
How much do we pay our nose to breathe?
你要付多少钱给鼻子呼吸？
Can we pay for it? It’s absurd, it’s ridiculous.
你能付钱吗？这是荒谬，可笑的
We cannot pay for it, we cannot, it’s a living process,
我们不能付钱给它，我们不能，这是个活生生的生命过程
you have to become, an egg has to become a chick.
你要成为，一只蛋必须变成小鸡
Now how much do you pay an egg to become a chick, or
你要付多少钱给蛋以令它变成小鸡，又或
how much does the egg pay to the mother for becoming a
一只蛋付多少钱给母亲以令自己
chicken?
成为小鸡？
It’s that ridiculous, but we never understand that living
就是这样荒谬可笑。我们从不明白活生生的生命是
things are so spontaneous.
那么自然而然
We never see living things, we live with matter,
我们从未看到有生命的东西，我们活在物质里
we live with the dead, not with the living things.
活在死物里，不是活在有生命的东西里
If you start watching a tree, you start watching a flower,
若你开始观看树木，观看花朵
how it becomes a fruit.
它怎样变成果实
You can’t even watch because it does it so slowly,
你甚至看不到，因为它们生长得很慢
you can’t even watch a flower becoming a fruit.
你看不到花朵怎样变成果实
Suddenly you find all coming up.
你忽然发现全都出现了
Like when I came to London from India I found all the
就如我从印度来到伦敦，我发觉所有树
trees were bare,
都是光秃秃的
absolutely like dry sticks, absolutely like dry sticks.
绝对像干枝，完全像干枝
Within a week, what I find is the green coming up;
不出一个星期，我发觉它们都变绿了
and within second week it was all lush,
到第二个星期，全都长得苍翠繁茂
you can’t believe it.
你不能相信
We never even notice, we take it for granted.
我们甚至未有留意到，我们视一切为理所当然
It’s happening. How does it happen?
它就在发生，是怎样发生的？
It’s a miraculous thing.
这是奇迹般的事情
If you see it, it’s miraculous how these flowers, for
若你看到，这是奇迹，这些花朵怎会…
example the particular flowers are only on a particular
例如一些特定的花朵只会生长在
tree and others, another, are on another tree.
特定的树上，另一些花朵生长在另一些树上？
How does it happen?
这是怎会发生的？
Who chooses them? Who puts them in proper shape?
谁拣选它们？谁把它们安放在合适的位置？
Who organizes all that?
谁在统筹？
And this is what one has to realize and
我们必须意识到
that is the All Pervading Power of God that does
是无所不在全能的神的力量，他成就所有
all the living work.
有生命的工作
And once you become that – the Spirit – then this power
一旦你也变成这样，即是灵，这个力量便会
starts flowing through you.
开始流通于你
You feel the power through you as Christ was touched
你感觉到这力量。就如基督被人触摸
and He said some power has gone to someone, like that.
他说︰「一些力量走到某人身上。」就像这样
You just become a medium of that power flowing.
你只是变成这力量流通的媒介
But you are empowered to maneuver it, to manage it,
你获授权调动它，管理它
to understand it.
了解它
You know completely about it, you know how to give it,
你知道它的一切，知道怎样给予它
you know to how to work it out, you know how to cure
怎样成就它
others, cure yourself.
怎样医治别人，医治自己
You know the complete working of your machinery.
你知道自己的机器如何运作
Apart from that, you get the powers to overcome all the
除此之外，你取得力量去克服
problems of your own machinery also.
自己的机器的所有问题
It’s so fantastic.
这是那么难以置信
Whole thing sounds very fantastic because we have
这样的事情看来难以置信，因为你从未
never seen this before.
看过这种事情发生
But to us it doesn’t sound fantastic when we see all these
但当你看到这些花朵忽然变成果实
flowers suddenly turning into fruits. It doesn’t sound.
对我们而言，并不是什么稀奇古怪的事情
But we see human beings turning into fruits,
若我们看到人类变成果实
then it sounds very fantastic, “How can that be?”
这才令人难以置信，怎会这样？
It has never happened before.
从未这样发生过
Only one person would get Realization and it was such a
只有一个人能得到自觉是很
difficult thing and nobody got it.
困难的事情，没有其他人能得到自觉
How is it today?
今天又怎样？
I say it is the blossom time which is been promised
我是说这是开花结果的时代，应许过的
which is been already prophesized.
亦曾被预言过的
Even a great poet in your country, William Blake,
即使你的国家一个伟大的诗人，威廉布莱克
has prophesized it.
也曾预言过
He said these times will come when men of God will
他说︰「时候到了，当有神性的人
become prophets
成为先知
and these prophets will have power to make other
这些先知有能力令他人
prophets. I mean nobody could be more precise
也变成先知。」我是说没有人能比
than Blake, I tell you. He was so great
布莱克说得更准确清晰，我告诉你，他是很
to say this will happen and this is what we have to expect
了不起的说︰「这会发生。」当我们追寻
when we go to anybody for seeking.
这是我们期望得到的
Have we become prophets? And what is a prophet?
我们是否已经成为先知？什么是先知？
Prophet is a person who is a collective being and
先知是集体的存在体
who knows all about it, who is the master.
他知道它的一切，他是导师
We call prophet a master.
我们叫先知为导师
And that’s what you have to become, the master.
你就是要成为…导师
And that mastery is very simple because
这种导师制度非常简单，因为
it’s all built within you, just it has to be connected.
全都在你内在建立好
Like, anything like a television set is to be connected to
只要把它连上。就像电视机
the mains, it’s all built in, it’s there, it just starts working.
接上总机，它全都装嵌好，就在那里，它便会开始运作
In the same way, you are that, you are that.
同样，你就是这样，你就是这样
Just it is to be connected.
只要与它连上
Whatever may be your caste, community, race,
不论你的种性、小区、种族
nationality, shapes, heights – anything, whatever you
国籍、型态、高度，不论什么
may be – makes no difference because all of you have
不论你是怎么样，都毫无分别，因为你们内在
got this great thing within you, this power of a rebirth
全都有这个了不起的装置，这种重生的力量
and you are to be born again, and you will be born again.
你要重生，你会重生
Why not today?
为什么不在今天？
There’s nothing to get angry, because people get angry
没有什么要动怒，人们有时生气是因为
sometimes because they don’t like anybody telling them
他们不喜欢某些人告诉他们
about something which of which they themselves are
一些他们感到
feeling bad.
不好的事情
They don’t like it.
他们不喜欢
For example if there’s a drunkard and he drinks too
例如，若有个酒鬼，他喝酒太多
much, he’s an alcoholic, he doesn’t like it
他是酒鬼，他不喜欢这样
and he feels bad, and if somebody tells him,
感觉很差，即使有人
even in the most gentlest way that “You’d better give up
很温和的告诉他︰「你最好把
drinking”, he doesn’t like it.
酒戒掉吧。」他不喜欢
But what I am saying is not that you should not do it,
我说的不是你不应这样做
I said it will happen that it just drops out.
我是说事情会是这样，他戒酒了
I don’t say, “You don’t do this” or “Don’t do that”
我不会说︰「你不要这样做，或不要那样做。」
but it just happens. And you must first understand what
它就是会发生，你要先明白
is the problem and how the problem is overcome.
问题出在哪里，可以怎样克服
That’s why I have to talk, otherwise there’s no need to
就是这个原因我才要谈及它，否则是完全
talk about it all, it just works out, it just works out
没有必要谈及它，它自会解决，它就是会解决
because you are just ready to have it and you just get it.
因为你已经准备就绪去得到它，你便取得它
I don’t do anything. I’m just a catalyst, I should say that
我什么也没有做，我只是催化剂，我要说
it works out.
它会成就到
I hope you’ll ask Me some questions about it first,
我希望你在得到自觉前，先向我
before we go in for any Realization.
提问一些有关的问题
If you have any questions, please ask. You must ask.
若你有任何问题，请发问，你必须发问
Yes?
是？
Man: Is there any difference to what You are saying and
男士︰你说的与导师摩诃罗渣(Maharaji)说的
what guru Maharaji …
是否有任何分别？
Who?
谁？
Man: Guru Maharaji
男士︰导师摩诃罗渣
Now, I’ll tell you one thing.
我告诉你
When you talk about any guru I don’t want to go into
当你谈及任何导师，我不想有
any controversies. All right? That’s first thing I’ll tell you
任何争论，好吗？此其一，我会告诉你
but I will tell you to ask yourself or ask anyone,
问问自己或问问其他人︰
“What has he done for anyone?”
「他为其他人做了些什么？」
Has he been able to give you any power,
他有否给你力量
or anyone the power? All right?
或给其他人力量，对吗？
Now, I can tell you all these who are here who are
我能告诉你所有在这里
realized souls who are here.
有自觉的灵
They are just like you to look at.
他们看来像你
Of course from face you can make out that they’re very
当然，从他们的脸容，你能分辨出他们
relaxed and very happy people.
很轻松，很快乐
But they can cure people,
他们能医治人
they can give Realization to people, they understand
能给人自觉，能明白
everything that is wrong with you and with themselves also,
你和自己的一切错误
So what has he done to your awareness?
这个人对你的知觉做了些什么？
Nothing.
什么也没做
Now, his disciples, what have they achieved?
现在，他的门徒有什么成就？
You ask them, “Where is the Kundalini of this person?
你问他们︰「这个人的灵量在哪里？
What is the problem of this lady or what is weighing
这个女士有什么问题，又或她脑海中
upon her mind?” They won’t be able to say.
什么是重要的？」他们没法回答
If you cannot even make out what’s wrong with another
若你连别人或自己有什么错
person or with yourself, how are you going to help?
也未能分辨出来，你又怎去帮助人
All such people, what do they do?
所有这类人，他们能做什么？
Let us see. Simple thing is that
让我们看看，简单的是
they can mesmerize you.
他们能催眠你
You may feel happy for awhile – it’s just like drinking.
你或许会快乐一会儿，就像喝酒
You know, if you drink, you feel happy.
你也知道，若你喝酒，便感到快乐
But, by drinking, what have we achieved?
喝酒让你有什么成就？
Have we become masters?
你能否成为导师？
All of them are like that.
他们所有人都像这样
You see, a decent women so obviously because he
你明白，他的意图很明显
asked for Rolls Royce.
因为他要求要劳斯莱斯(名车)
What is a Rolls Royce for a prophet?
对先知而言，劳斯莱斯算什么？
I mean what does it matter?
我是说有什么重要？
You see my point?
你明白哪里是重点吗？
This is so obvious, I mean this is so logically obvious.
这是很明显，我是说这是很合乎情理的明显
First of all, anybody who takes money from you is a
首先，任何拿你钱的人
parasite, simple as that.
都是寄生虫，就是这样简单
And to ask for Rolls Royce of all the things, you see.
要求一辆劳斯莱斯这类东西？你明白吗？
You have got Christ.
以基督为例
You can see from Christ’s life –
从基督的一生看到
will He care for your Rolls Royces?
他会在意你的劳斯莱斯吗？
To such a person, He’s a King, He doesn’t bother
这样的人物，他是王者，他不会在意
whether He has a Rolls Royce or not, whether He sleeps
不论他是否拥有劳斯莱斯，是否睡
on the ground or not, makes no difference.
在地上，都毫无分别
Such a person doesn’t care for anything,
这样的人物不在意什么
because He is in comfort, He’s got His own comfort.
因为他感到舒适，他拥有自己的舒适
He is a man of self-respect.
他有自尊
Do you think He would ask for anything whatsoever?
你认为他会否要求什么？
I mean it’s so obvious, for you people it is so obvious.
我是说这是很明显，对你们这是很明显
But when I talk to some people of this guru,
当我向一些人谈及这个导师
the particular one you are telling Me, they said,
这个你特别向我提及的导师，他们说︰
“ Mother, we give him the metal and he gives the Spirit.”
「母亲，我们给他一件金属，他给我们的却是灵。」
Can there be an exchange?
这样算是交换吗？
Can you purchase your Spirit?
你能否购买你的灵？
Use your logic, all right?
请用用你的逻辑思维，好吗？
God has given us brains to understand,
神给我们脑袋去理解
logically we can use that.
我们能逻辑地找到答案
Can you purchase, can you purchase the Spirit?
你能购买…你能购买灵吗？
Isn’t it so simple?
是这样简单吗？
We can't pay for it, my child, we cannot.
我的孩子，你不能用钱购买它，你不能
If you want to give Me a flower, all right.
若你想给我花朵，好吧
It’s just an expression of your love, and that’s all.
只是种表达爱的方式，就只是这样
But you can’t purchase Me. You can’t.
但你不能购买我，你不能
Your love can purchase Me, all right, that’s different.
你的爱却能购买我，好吧，这是不同的
But you can’t purchase Me with metal and money,
你不能用金属和钱来购买我
can you? What is a Rolls Royce?
你能吗？什么是劳斯莱斯？
I mean I don’t know what are all these crowns and
我是说我不懂这些王冠
things. What are they good for?
和类似的东西，它们有什么好处？
They don’t give you joy. Go and ask the people who
它们不能给你喜乐，你可以去问问
wear the crowns.
配戴王冠的人
The other day I was with Mrs. Thatcher.
前几天我与戴卓尔夫人一起
Poor thing, she was so miserable. Yes, she was!
可怜的家伙，她是那么痛苦。对，她很痛苦
You know I tried to sort of put her down, her vibrations.
我知道我在贬低她，她的生命能量
She was very miserable. We were just across the table
她很痛苦。我们隔着枱
talking to each other.
交谈
And what I was doing was to balance her - poor thing,
我做的是平衡她，可怜的家伙
she was very, she’s very upset.
她很苦恼
So, you must understand, you are too simple people,
你必须明白自己是很单纯的人
you are seekers of ancient times.
你们是远古的求道者
You are not seekers of today,
不是今天的求道者
And this time has been promised to you before, also.
这个时刻也是之前向你应许过的
And now you have to find it.
现在你要把它找出
Now you must keep your logic straight forward.
现在你要保持你的逻辑往前
I mean anybody who asks for Rolls Royce,
我是说任何人要求劳斯莱斯
I mean this is one of the stark examples I would say,
我的意思是这个例子很明显
cannot be any guru.
他不可能是导师
It’s the starkest one, absolutely one of the …
这是个很明显的例子，绝对是例子之一…
But there are subtler ones.
有些很精微的例子
He’s not so subtle.
他的并不那样精微
You will get out of it in no time, I know, all of you.
你会马上摆脱他，我知道，你们所有人
But the subtler ones are even worse.
那些精微的甚至更差
Some of them may not even ask for money.
他们一些人甚至没有要求金钱
May not.
或许没有
I don’t know of any, but there may be some because
我不认识任何这样的导师，但或许会有一些这样的人
I heard about someone who doesn’t now take money,
因为在印度，我听说
in India.
有些人不要钱
He has made money here and now he’s gone to India
他已在这里赚到钱，现在他走到印度
and he doesn’t take money from them.
再没有要他们的钱
But the one who has really not taken money,
那些人真的没有要钱
one person whom I know, has been using women.
我知道有一个人，他利用妇女
He’s not interested in money part,
他对钱没兴趣但他
he’s using your women.
却利用妇女
You see so this is what it is, you must understand.
你要明白，就是这样，你必须明白
His interest is not in your Spirit,
他感兴趣的不是你的灵
but in your purse or in your women. Imagine.
是你的钱包或是女人。试想像
How can holiness be combined with these dirty habits of
神圣又怎能和这些人的肮脏习性
people?
连系结合一起？
That means they themselves are under the control of their
意思是他们受他们的
desires which are anti-God.
欲望控制，那是违反神
These are all anti-God activities.
这些全是违反神的活动
And you people being so simple hearted, I tell you,
你们是那么天真无邪，我告诉你们
you’re so simple hearted!
你们是那么天真无邪
If you tell an Indian that a guru takes a Rolls Royce,
若你告诉印度人你的导师要劳斯莱斯
he said, “Eh.” Immediately they’ll answer.
他会说︰「呀…他们会马上回答
They don’t want this kind. How can they?
他们不想要这种导师，他们怎会这样？
Nobody will give to any guru in India.
在印度，没有人会给导师劳斯莱斯
Gurus have to pay people sometimes.
导师有时要付钱给人
First to entice them.
先诱骗他们
Westernized Indians, it’s different;
西化了的印度人，那是不同的
but those who are real Indians you see they are.
真正的印度人，你看他们是
People live with the mothers and they know what is
他们与母亲同住，他们懂分辨好坏
what. You know? Nobody can befool them,
你要明白，没有人能愚弄他们
they’re very practical people.
他们都很务实
Yes, my Child?
是，孩子
Woman: Can you be healed through faith?
女士︰信心能否把人治好？
The faith is two types –
信心有两种
what we call in Sanskrit is Shraddha is different from
梵文的 Shraddha (坚信)与你们称呼的
what you call as faith.
信心(faith)不同
In English they use it as “blind faith” and another as
英文他们称为「盲目的相信」，另一种
“faith.” All right? We can make it like that.
则是「信心」，对吗？我们可以这样分辨它们
Now, the blind faith is this, that “I have got faith in God
盲目的相信是这样︰「我对神有信心
and God will heal me.”
「神会治好我。」
This is one faith. All right?
这是其中一种信心，对吗？
Another is a faith which is enlightened where I say
另一种信心是开悟的信心，即当我说︰
you are the Spirit when you are connected.
「一旦你连上，你便是灵。」
Now, if you say that “I have faith in God”,
若你说︰「我对神有信心。」
you shouldn’t feel hurt when I tell you the truth, all right?
你不应因为我告诉你真相而感到受伤害，对吗？
Because if it is a blind faith means that you are not yet
因为若这是盲目的相信，即是说你仍未
connected with the power.
与大能连上
Not connected. See, now
仍未连上。明白吗
supposing I start saying,  “Christ, Christ, Christ, Christ!”
就如我说︰「基督，基督，基督，基督。」
Christ is not in my pocket.
基督不在我的口袋里
I can’t even meet a prime minister or a queen without
没有任何礼仪或联系又或类似的关系
having a protocol or a connection or some sort of a,
我甚至没法与首相或女王会面
you see, position or, we can say, a authority. Isn’t it?
你要明白，位置，或我们可以说，权力，对吗？
Now when we talk of anyone like that,
当我们像这谈论任何人
some people go on saying, “Rama, Rama, Rama.
有些人不断的说︰「罗摩，罗摩，罗摩
Krishna, Krishna.” You see These are all Incarnations
克里希纳，克里希纳。」你要明白，他们全是降世神祇
and Christ is the Son of God,
基督是神的儿子
He is the Son of a King and you just can’t meet Him.
他是国王的儿子，你就是没法会见他
You can’t just call Him.
你是不能叫喊他
He’s not at your beck and call,
他不会在你背后叫你
He’s not your servant. All right?
他也不是你的仆人，对吗？
Now to having faith like that when you are not
拥有这样的信心，当你仍未
connected, if you are healed, you are healed by some
连上，若你痊愈，你必定是被
other agencies, not by Christ.
其他媒体治好，不是基督
But if you are a realized soul and then you are healed,
若你是有自觉的灵而又痊愈
then it is done by Christ.
就是基督把你治好
I’ll tell you a difference,
我会告诉你有何差别
a very clear cut difference of healing.
医疗功用的直接清晰的差别
We have in England – we had, I don’t know now if you
在英国我们有…我不知道现在还有没有
have that one, it’s an organization called a
一个名为「已故梁医生
International Curative Center of Late Dr. Lang.
国际治病中心」的机构
Now this Dr. Lang was dead, I mean he was late
这个梁医生已经去世，我是说虽然他已去世
but he had a curative center.
却拥有一个治病中心
You see, and this gentleman died
这个男士已经死了
and he possessed a man in Vietnam, a soldier,
他附上一个在越南的人，一个士兵
not his own son but a soldier.
不是他的儿子，而是士兵
Now this soldier was told by this fellow – I mean,
这个人告诉这个士兵，我是说
they’re very honest people, being English,
他们都是非常诚实的人，作为英国人
they are honest and they tell the truth, you see.
他们都很诚实，都说实话。你要明白
They don’t say that “we do it through God” or anything.
他们不说︰「我们透过神或其他做的。」
So he told that there are many doctors
所以他说︰「有很多医生…」
(I hope the doctors won’t mind) who have died and who
我希望那些医生不介意，他已经死了
were very ambitious are still wanting to cure people.
却仍很有野心，仍想医治人
And he should “Go back to my son and tell him all the
他应「找我的儿子，告诉他
story that I’ve come in you and my son will believe.”
我附在你身上，我的儿子会相信你。」
So he said, “How will he believe me?”
他说︰「他怎会相信我？」
He said, “No, no. I will tell you some secrets
他说︰「不，不，我会告诉你
which only he and me, both of us share.
一些只有他和我知道的秘密，我们分享的秘密
So he’ll definitely believe you.”
因此他肯定相信你。」
So this fellow agreed. He was a very healthy fellow,
这家伙同意，他是个很健康的家伙
actually this spirit entered into him when he got into a
实际上，他突然有些震动，这个亡灵
sudden shock,
就附上他身上
something he saw which shocked him in the war and this
他看到某些战争中令他震惊的事情
spirit entered.
这亡灵便进入了他
And he was carried by that spirit somehow or other to
他不知怎的把这个亡灵
England where he met his son
带到英国，与他的儿子会面
and he told the whole story.
他告诉他整个故事
And the son had to believe because
儿子必须相信，因为
he knew so many secrets.
他知道很多秘密
And they started this curative center.
他们便开展这个治病中心
Now how do I come to know of late Mr. Lang
我是怎样知道去世的梁先生
is the thing.
是这样？
They cured a lady who was in India – long time back
他们治好一个在印度的女士，我告诉你
it was 1970 I’m telling you –
这是很久以前，1970年
and she came to see Me, and she was all shaking,
她来见我时，不停的抖动
nervous, she’s like this.
很神经质，她就像这样
I said, “What’s this?”
我说︰「怎会这样？」
She said, “I was sick with a certain disease and
她说︰「我染上某些疾病
I was afraid of an operation and I came to know about
我害怕动手术，我知道
this organization, I wrote to them
有这个机构，便写信给他们
and they wrote to me saying that "At this time on this
他们回复︰「在这天的
date we’ll enter into your body."
这个时间，我们会进入你的身体。」」
Openly, I mean they don’t say that
公开的说，我是说他们没有说︰
“We are God” or anything.
「我们是神。」或类似的话
“We’ll enter into your body and you’ll feel a little
「我们会进入你的身体，你会感到
shaking, doesn’t matter,
有些抖动，不要紧
and you’ll sleep off and we’ll work it out.”
接着你睡觉，我们便能把你治好。」
And she said, “I got cured of that disease.”
她说︰「我的病痊愈了。」
But after three years or so,
大约三年后
the whole body started shaking and she couldn’t bear it
她整个身体开始抖动，她不能
anymore and she came to see Me.
再忍受，所以来见我
That’s how I came to know about Dr. Lang, you see,
我就是这样知道梁先生，你要明白
that he had – this poor lady was tortured for three years,
他是…这个可怜的女士受了三年的折磨
she suffered so much and then she came to see Me.
她受很多苦，跟着她来见我
So after Mr. Lang entered into her body – Dr. Lang –
在梁先生进入她的身体后，梁医生
it was after six years that she came to see Me because
六年后她来见我，因为
three years she was all right,
开始的三年她没有不妥
and after three years it started.
三年后才开始不妥
And that’s how I came to know all the spirits that had
我就是这样知道附在她身上的
entered into her, the doctors and all that.
所有亡灵，那些医生和所有一切
It was a horrible case.
很可怕的个案
Of course she got cured later on, no doubt.
当然，她之后被治好，毋庸置疑
Because when you become the Spirit,
因为当你成为灵
you are in your fort, nobody can enter into your body.
你在你的堡垒内，没有人能进入你的身体
You become something which doesn’t get contaminated,
你变得不受污染
doesn’t get over powered, nobody can dominate.
不受人控制，没有人能操控你
And that’s how she got cured.
这就是为何她能痊愈
So with faith, if somebody says,
透过信心，若有人说︰
“Oh, you will be healed” you see
「噢，你的病会痊愈。」你要明白
and they start shouting and screaming and this and that,
他们开始叫喊，尖叫，这样那样做
and suddenly you might feel, maybe there’s a spirit.
你或许忽然感到，或许那里有个亡灵
They replace also sometimes these spirits,
他们有时会取代这些亡灵
it’s very surprising.
这是很令人惊讶
They can replace a spirit from one to another.
他们能用一个亡灵取代另一个亡灵
I’ve seen such cases also.
我也曾经见过这样的情况
All kinds of things I have seen in spirits.
我见过亡灵各式各样的情况
The other day, only about eight days back, wasn’t that,
前几天，约八天前
Marie, when this charismatic fellow came in?
玛利亚，这个有魅力的家伙什么时候来过？
Eight days back in France a gentleman came in.
八天前在法国，有个男士来
Young fellow, must be about twenty-four or so,
年青的小伙子，约二十四岁
he got into such a big agitation and started crying and
他很激动，开始叫喊
funny type of a thing that I’ve never seen a spirit enter
我从未见过亡灵附上他身上这种
into him.
有趣情况
Whole body was shaking. And I mean he fell down,
他整个身体都在抖动，我是说他跌倒
he started crying, weeping, all sorts of things happened.
开始哭闹，哭泣，做出各种动作
And he said that “I went to charismatic movement where
他说︰「我是在有魅力运动里
I got it.” And then they get it
被它附上。」他们也被附上
and they think Holy Ghost has entered into them.
还以为圣灵进入了他们身上
Now just imagine.
试想像
How can Holy Ghost make you miserable?
圣灵怎会令你悲伤不快？
I don’t know from where these ideas come in.
我不知道这种想法从何而来
And poor child, you know, he suffered so much.
这个可怜的孩子，你也知道，他受很多苦
Now he’s all right.
现在他没事
But he couldn’t believe it that you could be all right
他却不相信自己能没事
because he thought … and then they say,
因为他以为…接着他们说︰
“These are your sins and you have to get over your sins
「这是你的罪(sin)，你要摆脱你的罪
and this is why you are, what’s happening to you,
这就是为何你出现这种状况，什么事发生在你身上
you still have done bad karmas, and this and that.
你仍作一些坏的业(karmas)。」诸如此类
But your bad karmas and all those things can be solved
当灵量升起，你的坏业报和所有这些事情
when the Kundalini rises.
都能获得解决
There is a center for this specially which is really
有一个能量中心特别为此而设
being adorned by Jesus Christ here.
它在这里以耶稣基督来装饰
Did you tell them, about this center?
你有没有告诉他们
All right.
好吧
So this is the center and when the Kundalini passes
当灵量穿透这个能量中心
through that – that’s why they say that you have to pass
这就是为何他们说「你必须
through it.
穿透它。」
He gets awakened and when He gets awakened all these
他被唤醒，当他醒来
two pouches you see there of ego and superego,
这两个小袋，你看到这个自我和超我
your conditioning and all your left sided problems
你的制约，你左边和
and right sided problems are sucked in.
右边的问题都会被吸入
That’s why they said that He died for our sins.
这就是为何他们说︰「他为我们的罪而死。」
He’s described in the ancient Indian scriptures as
印度的古老经典描述他为
Mahavishnu but you see very –
摩诃毗湿奴，但你看到很多…
the missionaries went to India they gave a very wrong
很多传教士到印度，他们带来完全错的
picture of Christ, absolutely wrong picture,
基督形象，完全错的形象
so they were still expecting Mahavishnu to come in.
所以他们仍然期待摩诃毗湿奴会来
And this is what it is.
就是这样
He’s supposed
按照传教士的说法
to be, according to missionaries, somebody who sort of
他应该是某种
converts people and all that nonsense. See?
会转化人的人，这全是谬误，你明白吗？
It’s not the real thing, that
不是真的
He is to be awakened within you.
他要在我们内里被唤醒
He said that. He said, “I have to be born within you.”
他说︰「我要在你们内里出生。」
And that is what it is.
就是这样
When Kundalini rises, She awakens that center within us
灵量升起之际，她唤醒我们内在的能量中心
and all our conditionings and egos are sucked in,
我们的一切制约和自我都会被吸入
a space is created here in the fontanel bone area through
在这里的脑囟骨区会创造出一个空间
which the Kundalini comes in and you can feel the cool
灵量透过这个空间上升，你能感到凉风
breeze from your head coming out.
从你头顶走出来
That’s what it is, and you feel it in your hands.
就是这样，你也能在双手感到凉风
It’s not just that you’re mad after someone, you see?
这不只是你对某人狂热，明白吗？
It isn’t like that.
不是这样
It’s not that way, you see,
不是这样，明白吗？
nothing of that kind.
绝对不是这样
You become a self-respecting, normal, dignified
你变成有自尊，正常，有尊贵的
personality of great spiritual value which you are.
人格的伟大灵性价值，你是这样
All right?
对吗？
So this is what faith is and what is blind faith is.
这就是信心，也是盲目的相信
Yes, my child.
是，孩子？
Man: It seems very difficult the concept that Self
男人︰这看来很困难，自觉
Realization doesn’t involve some personal effort.
这概念不牵涉个人的努力
Can it really come to anybody in effect of how
任何人是否真的都能得到自觉，不管他们
materialistic they are? Am I understanding this?
是如何唯物主义？我的理解对吗？
Yes, it appears on the face of it very difficult
对，表面看来它是很困难
and how people are materialistic is also true no doubt,
人们很唯物主义也是事实，这是毋庸置疑
but Spirit is much stronger than the matter
但灵比物质强得多
and when It has to express,
当它要表达自己
It completely crushes all that and It comes.
便会砸碎一切，升上来
Now we have here, most of you are English people,
我们现在在这里，你们大部分是英国人
I should say, westernized, very materialistic people they
我应说西方人，都是很唯物主义
are there. I should say I mean living in that world,
我是说活在这个世界
they may not have been that materialistic because if they
他们或许并不那样唯物主义，因为
are not seekers, they would not come to Me.
若他们不是求道者，便不会来找我
But a new being has been born.
新的存在体已经诞生
If you look at an egg you feel,
若你看着一只蛋，你会感到︰
“Oh, what a hard stuff is this!”
「噢，那么坚硬的东西？」
But if it is broken at the right moment,
若在合适的时刻打破它
with the right understanding, it becomes a bird.
以合适的理解，它变成一只鸟
Because a living process is all, only the last breakthrough
因为活生生的生命过程全是这样
has to take place.
只有最后的突破要发生
Apparently it looks difficult, but to Me it is not.
表面看来这是很困难，对我却并不困难
Perhaps I know the job.
或许因为我懂这工作
All right?
对吗？
Yes, it looks … many people have said all kinds of
对，它看来…人们说各种
things about Kundalini, also.
关于灵量的事情
I must say some books I have seen have horrified.
我必须要说，我曾经读过一些书籍，令我很吃惊
You see if you don’t know the job, everything –
你要明白，若你不懂这工作，一切…
supposing if somebody else doesn’t know how to drive a
就如有人不懂驾车
car, you see, and he gets into the car
他坐在车里
the way he’d describe it would be horrifying.
他描述的路径是会令人恐惧的
You’d never get near a car, isn’t it? It’s like that.
你永远不会走近汽车，对吗？就像这样
The one who is not authorized and does not know the job
没有获授权，不懂这工作的人
should not do it.
不应做这工作
But that’s what happens to you, that you become
发生在你身上的，就是
the Spirit, you become your own master
你变成灵，变成自己的导师
and you become the master of this art –
变成艺术的大师
the master of this art.
这种艺术的大师
Yes, my child?
是，孩子？
I couldn't hear you?
我听不清楚
You mentioned hypnosis earlier and You also said that
女士︰你之前提及催眠，你也有提及
You regarded Yourself as a catalyst and
你视自己为催化剂
don’t You think that the hypnotist also regards himself as
你是否认为施行催眠的人也视自己为
a catalyst?
催化剂？
Yes, Yes no doubt.
对，对，毫无疑问
Yes, yes that’s true, but the difference is this,
对，对，这是事实，但分别在于
that the hypnotist brings you under his power,
施催眠的人控制你
he doesn’t give you any power or no dimension to your
他既没有给你力量亦没有给你新的
awareness - you see?
知觉向度，明白吗？
There’s a tremendous difference between the two.
二者有极大的差别
You see, you have got your own power within you.
你要明白，你取得你内在的力量
Say, for example, all right, your Spirit there.
例如，好吧，你的灵在这里
Now I’m a catalyst, you see, you can use a spoon for
现在，我是催化剂，你能用一只匙
giving a poison or could use it for giving a nectar,
来给予毒药又能用它给予甘露
all right?
对吗？
So if you give the nectar, then it’s a great thing;
所以，若你能给予甘露，这会是很好
and if you give the poison, it’s horrible. It’s like that.
但若你给予毒药，这会是很可怕的，情况就像这样
Now the hypnotist uses hypnosis –
施催眠的人利用催眠
how does he hypnotize is the point.
问题是他怎样催眠你
What he does is to push you into your subconscious,
他是把你推向潜意识，令你进入
into your collective subconscious
集体潜意识
where he overpowers you. You are under his power.
他便能控制你。你在他的淫威下
He says, “You become like a child”, you become like a child.
他说︰「变得像小孩。」你便变得像小孩
“You suck a little bottle”, you do it.
「吸吮一个小瓶子。」你便依他的话去做
What’s all this?
这些是什么？
But here you become the Spirit in the sense that you
但在这里，你成为灵，某程度上你
become collectively conscious.
成为集体意识
It’s no hypnosis because you, yourself, can feel it.
不是被催眠，因为你能感觉到它
Now, say example you take ten children
就如你找十个
who are realized souls.
有自觉的孩子
There are some children who are realized souls,
有些孩子是有自觉的灵
even little children.
即使年纪很小
And you take them near a person who is suffering from
你带他们走近
some trouble, all right?
有毛病的人，对吗？
Now you tie up their eyes and ask them,
你把他们双眼蒙上，问他们︰
“What’s the problem of this gentleman?”
「这个男士有什么问题？」
They will raise the same fingers, all of them
他们会举起同一根手指，他们全部人
will raise the same fingers and say, “This is burning”,
举起同一根手指说︰「这根手指像火烧。」
you see, because the sensation you feel – of burning,
因为你有像被火烧
of numbness or of cool breeze,
麻痹或凉风的感觉
a new awareness of a vibratory nature is born within you.
一种有生命能量的品质的新知觉在你内里诞生
Not with hypnosis, on the contrary, after hypnosis you
不是催眠。受催眠后你的反应却是相反
feel so tired and finished as if somebody has been riding
你会感到既无生气又像要完蛋
your horse.
就像有人欺骗控制你
It’s just the other way around.
情况是刚好相反
And you start growing into you and understanding,
你开始成长，了解自己
you can cure people you understand what are the centers
你能为别人医治
that are catching,
你既能了解自己
you understand what are the centers of another person
亦能了解别人的那个能量中心
that are catching.
有阻塞
In the beginning sometimes people have confusion, I've seen,
开始时，人们有时会感到混乱，我曾经见过
that they don’t know “whether these are my
他们分辨不出︰「是我的能量中心
centers or your centers.”
还是别人的能量中心有阻塞。」
Now we have ways and methods by which you can
我们有方法
discriminate.
让你能分辨
You can see which are your centers catching and which
你能知道是你的能量中心
are the centers the other person catching.
还是别人的能量中心有阻塞
You also know how to get them all right,
你也知道怎样令它妥当
you also know how to give Realization to others,
亦知道怎样给别人自觉
and to empower them with their own powers.
授权他们取得他们自己的力量
It’s just the opposite.
情况刚刚相反
But catalyst could be horrifying,
催化剂可以是很可怕
and catalyst could be just heavenly.
亦可以是极之美好
Question: Can some people
男士︰「自觉」是否能
Self Realize themselves with their own effort?
完全透过个人的努力得到？
With their own effort?
透过自己的努力？
I don’t think it’s possible, you see, because
我想不可能，就像
like a light which is enlightened can only enlighten
就像已经点亮的光
another light.
才能点亮其他光
But what I’m saying, that even supposing like Buddha,
我是说即使是像佛陀这样的人物
you see, He got His Realization when He was
他在完全疲累下
absolutely tired and He had to have it.
得到自觉，他必须得到它
Of course the Holy Ghost did that. He could not have
当然，是圣灵赐予他自觉
done it on Him,
他自己没法做到
but He got the Realization there because it was a
他得到自觉，因为那是
different circumstance which He had to live,
不同的处境，他必须活着
He didn’t have to talk about God,
他不必谈神
He didn’t have to talk about the whole thing,
不必谈整件事情
because people were so much engaged in talking of big
因为人们忙于谈论很多大事
things like God and about all kind of deities, this, that,
如神，各种神祇，这样那样
there was a big confusion.
因此有极大的混乱
And somebody was to be Realized at that time
那时有人意识到这种情况
who would just localize it and say, “Only Self
他因此使它具地方色彩，说︰「只要自觉
Realization – don’t talk of God or anything, forget it.”
不要谈神或其他，忘记它吧。」
That’s why He got Realization like that.
这就是为何他能这样得到自觉
But you cannot get Realization just like that –
但你却不能像这样得到自觉
only possession you can get. You cannot.
你只会着魔，却不能得到自觉
Somebody who is an enlightened soul,
开悟的灵
such an enlightened soul doesn’t take money from you.
开悟的灵不会拿取你任何金钱
Normally, you see, people don’t want to give you Relization -
正常的情况，你要明白，他们不想给你自觉
ninety-nine percent of those who are really realized,
九成九真正有自觉的人
they’ll throw stones at you,
他们会向你抛石
they won’t have anything to do because their experiences
他们什么也不想做，因为他们
of human beings are horrifying.
与人类交往的经验是很可怕的
If you go and talk to them, they’ll tell Me, they told Me
若你与他们交谈，他们会告诉我，他们告诉我︰
that “Wait for twelve years.
「等了十二年
See, Mother, they will all finish You off, they’ll kill You,
母亲，你要明白，他们会令你完蛋，会杀死你
they’ll do this.”
他们会这样做。」
It’s very venturesome to deal with human beings because
与人类交往是很冒险的
they’ll be very egoistical and they will never accept you.
因为他们很自我中心，永远也不会接受你
But if you take like this, like
若你这样处理
somebody who knows is a help, isn’t it?
就像有人知道这是个帮忙，对吗？
And Realization is not possible, is not possible to be
自觉是不可能的
done by yourself.
不可能自己给自己自觉
It’s not possible, because if a, say, a candle which is not
不可能的。就如…就如一枝
enlightened wants to get itself enlightened,
未点亮的蜡烛想点亮自己
the light has to be brought, isn’t it?
必须把光带来才行，对吗？
It’s so simple like that.
就是这样简单
But one should not feel bad about it, actually.
实际上我们不应有坏感觉
See, I don’t know how to drive, somebody drove Me down here.
就如我不懂驾驶，有人驾车把我带来这里
I didn’t feel bad that he had to drive Me down, did I?
我不会因为他载我来而感到不好，我有吗？
And I only know one job.
我只懂一项工作
I don’t know many.
我懂得不多
Many jobs I don’t know, I don’t know how to operate
很多工作我都不懂，我不懂银行怎样运作
bank, I don’t know how to write a check,
不懂怎样写支票
I’m hopeless in many things.
我对很多事情都很无知
I don’t know how to open a can, maybe.
或许，我连怎样开罐头也不懂
But I know how to open the Kundalini. All right?
我却懂怎样提升灵量，对吗？
So if I know one job, why should you mind?
所以若我只懂一项工作，你又怎能介意？
After all, we depend on each other for everything, isn't it?
毕竟我们互相依赖，对吗？
So why not, if I know the job, what’s the harm?
所以为什么不能？若我懂这项工作，有什么所谓？
And you will know, too.
你们也会懂
But it cannot be done by yourself.
但这却不能由你来做
But actually in this you’re not obliged for anything.
事实上，你不需要做任何事
I just do it because I love it.
是我来做，因为我爱它
It’s just emits, I don’t do anyway, I’m just flowing,
它只是散发，不管怎样也不是我做的，我只是在流通
I don’t know how it happens, just it’s flowing.
我不知道它是怎会发生，只是在流通
I just love for love’s sake.
我是为爱而爱
You can’t believe such a person can exist,
你们不会相信有这种人存在
but I do really, I am like that.
但我却真的是这样，我就像这样
Sometimes you might even, some of the Sahaja Yogis
你有时甚至会…有些霎哈嘉瑜伽士
do feel that I’m too compassionate and that I should be
认为我过分慈悲，我应对人和对
rather strict with people and things like that, you see.
这样的事情严厉。你要明白
They come and tell Me some wisdom about it.
他们告诉我怎样处理应付它的一些智慧
You see they think I’m not so practical,
他们认为我不务实
but this is the most practical thing.
但这却是最务实的事
Yes, I know they make mistakes because they
对，我知道他们犯错，因为他们
don't know they are walking in darkness.
不知道自己走在黑暗中
If you are walking in darkness, you will bang at something.
若你在黑暗中行走，你会碰到东西
Then only thing you can do is to have compassion for
你唯一要做的是对他们慈悲
them because they can’t see, they are blind. Isn’t it?
因为他们看不见，他们是盲的，对吗？
How can you have any anger or temper?
你又怎能动怒或发脾气呢？
And moreover, I would request you not to have any
还有，我请求你们不要
misidentification with anyone whatsoever.
对任何人有错误的认同
You have to get to your Spirit, that’s the main thing.
你要到达你的灵，这才重要
If you still think of somebody, you see,
若你仍想着某人，你要明白
like the lady – I don’t know, somebody might have sent
像一个女士，我也不知道，或许有人把她
her here, maybe. I don’t know why she got angry.
叫来这里，我不知道她为何生气
I didn’t say anything to hurt her.
我没有说任何伤害她的话
May be she is possessed.
或许她被鬼附上
I don’t know why she has got angry with Me,
我不知道她为何生我气
and she just got up and just walked off saying that
她只是站起来，说︰
“You’re telling everything lies.”
「谎话连篇。」
Why should I tell you lies?
我为何要向你说谎？
I don’t have to get anything out of you.
我不需要拿取你什么
But why it happens?
但为什么会发生？
Because she’s not sensitive,
因为她不敏锐
she’s not sensitive to Divinity.
对神圣不敏锐
She doesn’t understand who’s Divine, who’s...
她不理解谁是上天，谁…
I don’t blame her.
我不会责怪她
She hasn’t got the sensitivity. It’s a caliber.
她未有这个敏锐度，这是种才干水平
I have seen Sahaja Yogis now of different varieties
我现在见到的霎哈嘉瑜伽士，
have come to Me.
有不同类别的来见我
Some of them are of such a caliber you can’t even believe.
你甚至不相信他们有些人是那么有才干
They get into Realization, they know what it is,
他们得到自觉，知道自觉是什么
they have the pattern just like a diamond,
他们的样式就像钻石
they get it and they get to it.
他们取得它，得到它
They’re tremendous people.
他们是极棒的人
There are some who slog behind.
有些人步履艰难在后面
Some of them who get Realization but still
有些人虽然得到自觉
they go on doubting. All kinds.
却不停质疑，各式各样的人都有
Doesn’t matter. I love all of them.
但不要紧，我爱他们
Yes, my child?
对，孩子？
He is a Sahaja yogi?
他是霎哈嘉瑜伽士吗？
If before Realization we were such a horrible person that
男士︰母亲，若在自觉前，我们都是可怕的人
we gave cancer to everybody we met or something like
会把癌带给我们遇见的人，或会发生类似的事情
this, after Realization does the effects of that get taken
在自觉后，这种影响会否消失
away, or what happens?
或什么会发生？
Yah. I know it, so many things have happened.
对，我知道有很多事情发生
We had somebody in Brighton, you remember –
在布莱顿有个人，你记得他吗？
he’s here right now, I think –
他现在在这里
who was drunk when he came in.
我想他来时喝醉了
He was very angry with Me, you see, to begin with.
他开始时很生我的气
He said, “How can I get rid of this trouble?
他说︰「我怎能摆脱这种麻烦？
I can’t believe You”, and all that.
我不相信你。」就是这样
And he’s all right, perfectly all right.
跟着他妥当了，完全妥当了
His change is so beautiful, you can’t… is he there?
他的改变是那么可爱，你不能相信，他在吗？
Yogi: Yes , I am.
瑜伽士：「是，我在」
May God bless you.
愿神祝福你
He’s so sweet now.
他现在很可爱
The other day he came to see Me.
有天他来见我
I said, “Look at that. He’s so sweet.”
我说︰「看看他，他是那么可爱。」
He was a very sweet man, wasn’t he?
他是个可爱的人，是吗？
But something had put him up, made him upset, you see,
但有些事情困扰他，令他很沮丧
that he became alcoholic, you see.
他因此酗酒，你要明白
He’s all right.
他会妥当
The compassion can only make you understand that
慈悲令你明白
there’s a reason for this –
事出必有因
He is a very sweet person, very sweet person no doubt.
他是个好人，毫无疑问是个很好的人
But something had gone wrong with him.
他必定有些不妥
It’s all right.
会妥当的
So this happens, it’s true.
有这样的事情发生，千真万确
Sahaja Yogis realize this.
霎哈嘉瑜伽士知道这些事情
Some, of course, I must say, go little bit.
一些霎哈嘉瑜伽士，当然，我必须要说，只要多走一步
Doesn’t matter. They’ll come up, all of them will come,
不要紧，他们会迎上来，所有人都会迎上来
I’m sure of it.
我肯定
Everyone is made for it.
每个人都是为此被创造
Actually, the Divine is anxious to give you Realization –
事实上，上天很渴望给你们自觉
much more, much more anxious than you are.
比你更想更想给你自觉
If there were thousand people today,
若今天这里有上千人
I would have given them Realization better.
我更能给他们自觉
But very few people take to reality, you see now.
可惜很少人喜欢实相，你看现在
That guru maharaji, thousands are like mad after him,
那个导师摩诃罗渣(Maharaj)，上千人像疯子一样追随他
isn’t it?
对吗？
He’s given nothing to the poor people.
他什么也没给那些可怜人
But for reality, there are very few.
就实相而言，可惜很少人喜欢
Like other day somebody asked Me a question,
像有天有人问我︰
“Mother, why don’t You do it to everyone?”
「母亲，你为何不给每个人自觉？」
I said, “Where are they, everyone?
我说︰「他们在哪里？每个人！
They are busy. Where are they?
他们很忙，他们在哪里？」
In this Brighton, how many there are?
有多少人在布莱顿？
How many are here?
有多少人在这里？
All right? That’s the problem.
对吗？这就是重点
It takes time for people to love reality. Time.
要花点时间人们才喜欢实相，需要点时间
It’s such a beautiful thing.
它是这样美好的东西
And even they get realized, then they drop out, you see.
即使他们得到自觉，却轻易放弃，你明白吗？
They say, “Oh, I’m all right now. I’m all right.”
他们说︰「噢，我现在很好，我很好。」
After one year they’ll appear.
一年后，他们再次出现
That’s not the way.
不应是这样
You have to master this art, absolutely master it.
我们要掌握这艺术，完全掌握它
It is all free, absolutely free.
那全是免费，完全免费
Now they are all sitting down here, they can say that.
他们现在全都仍坐在这里，他们可以这样说
Would You talk a bit more about Self Realization and
男士︰你可否多谈一点自觉
what’s necessary to enhance that.
有什么需要做去增强它
Yes, Yes, I will be in my next lecture, one by one.
好，好，我会在下次的讲座里说，一个一个课题的说
Now I’m talking the left side, the right side,
我现在说左脉，然后右脉
and then the center, and then also, of course,
接着是中脉，当然还有灵
about the Spirit.
这是肯定的
Definitely, hundred times, that’s what I have to do.
上千次。我会这样做
But gradually I have to build you up. All right?
我必须慢慢把你建立巩固好，好吗？
I will definitely. You won’t believe,
我肯定会，你不会相信
I think I have given five hundred lectures already
我想我已经在
in London, at least. And it doesn’t end.
伦敦至少有五百个讲座，但并未完结
Every time, they say last time I spoke they said,
每一次，每次我说完后，他们都说︰
“Mother it was absolutely a new dimension
「母亲，你谈及的绝对是
You talked about”, you see.
新的角度。」你看
I don’t know, Kerry told Me first time he touched his
我也不知道，卡告诉我，在我的讲座，他第一次
vibrations so much with my lecture
感到有那么多的生命能量
I don’t know what I touched him so much.
我不知道为何我那么感动他
Yes, it’s surprising.
对，这是令人惊叹
He’s from Australia.
他是来自澳洲
Australians do well. Very fast work.
澳洲人做得很好，很快
So, all the questions are over now? Should we have it?
现在问完了吗？我们要得到它吗？
What are karmas?
问题︰什么是业报(karma)？
Karmas are when you do any work or anything with your
业报是当你
right side action then
以右脉的力量来做任何事
the effects of that accumulate within you as an ego
它的效果在你内里积累为自我
because you think you are doing it.
因为你以为是你做的
Actually, we don’t do anything substantial.
事实是我们没有做什么实在的事情
What we do is a dead work like as I said we make a chair
我们做的只是死的。就如我说︰「我们用
out of a dead, a tree.
一棵已死的树来造椅子
That’s all we do. What work we do is an idea we have
我们就是做这种事。」我们做的是以为
we are doing work.
自己在做这事情
What work are you doing?
我们做了些什么？
Can you convert this into a fruit?
你能否把这些转成果实？
We can’t even put fragrance into it.
我们甚至不能令它芬芳
So this myth, you see, works as ego within us as shown
所以这种幻象，你看，在我们内在以自我运作
here, which I will be speaking tomorrow about, all right?
在这里显现，我明天会谈及它，好吗？
And this is what is that we think we are doing this work,
这就是我们以为自己在做着这工作
that work, and this ego thinks that if you have done bad
那工作，这个自我以为若你做好事或坏事
work or good work we have to suffer.
你便要受苦
You see, a tiger doesn’t feel that way.
你要明白，老虎不会有这种感觉
If tiger has to eat, it must kill.
若老虎要吃，它必须杀戮
It kills the animal, eats it, finished.
杀死动物，吃掉它，就这样
It doesn’t sit down and sulk, “Oh, God, I shouldn’t have
它不会坐下想︰「噢，天呀！我不该
done it. I should become vegetarian.”
这样做，我要成为素食者。」
It doesn’t accumulate any, any, any karmas in it,
它不会积累任何业
all right? But we human beings do. Why?
对吗？但人类却会，为什么？
Because we are closed.
因为我们是封闭的
We are closed. See here, we are closed.
我们是封闭的。看看这里，我们是封闭的
They are open.
它们却是开放的
Whatever they do, they are not bothered.
无论它们做什么，都毫不在意
But we are bothered about what we do
我们却在意自己在做什么
because we think we do.
因为我们以为是我们做的
And when, as I said, this center is opened out
但当…就如我说︰这个能量中心开启了
He sucks our karmas, and the so-called karmas are
它吸入我们的业。那个所谓的业
nothing but sins, you see –
–只是罪，你要明白
in a biblical language we can call it as sin, you see.
按圣经的说法，我们可以称它为罪
And they’re all sucked in
它们全都被那位在我们内里被唤醒
by this powerful Deity of Christ awakened within us.
很有力量的神祇基督所吸入，我们因此超越它
And you get beyond it because
因为业是
it is the ego that does the karma.
自我做的
When your ego is finished, where are the karmas?
当你的自我完蛋，业又在哪里？
They are finished, too.
它们也完蛋了
Then you don’t say, “I did it.”
你便不会说︰「我做的。」
What you will say, “Mother, it’s not working out.
你会说︰「母亲，它没有成就
It’s not going up.” Now what is this “it” –
它并不往上走。」这个「它」是什么？
it becomes a third person. “It’s flowing.
它变成第三者。「它在流通
The vibrations not coming.”
没有生命能量。」
You see, you don’t say, “I, I am doing this Realization.
你看，你不会说︰「我在做自觉
I am raising the kunda ..”, they don’t say so.
我在提升灵量…」。他们不会这样说
They say, “It’s not rising.” You become a third person.
他们说︰「它没有升上来。」你变成旁观者
That third person is the Spirit.
这个旁观者是灵
Where you do not say that “I should do it.”
你不会说︰「我必须这样做。」
Even if it’s your son, you say,
即使是你的儿子，你会说︰
“Mother, it’s better he gets Realization.”
「母亲，他最好先得到自觉。」
All right. You’ll see. Try it. It didn’t work out?
好吧？你看，试试吧。但成就不了
All right, then should I give a certificate?
好吧，我是否要发证书？
He said, “How can You give certificate,
他说︰「母亲，你怎能发证书？
Mother, how can anybody, Kundalini has not risen.”
任何人怎能？灵量还未升起。」
Everyone knows, you see, whether it’s your father,
每个人都知道，你要明白，无论是你的父亲
mother, sister - anyone –
母亲、姊妹、任何人
if they’re not realized, they know they’re not realized,
若他们未得自觉，他们知道自己未得自觉
so what. They just know.
那又如何，他们就是知道
This granddaughter of Mine, who was …
我这个外孙女，她是…
she’s here now, she is a born realized,
她现在在这里，她出生已有自觉
and she was hardly about five years of age, I think,
还不到五岁，当他们
when they went to Ladakh.
到Ladakh
There was one lama sitting with a shaved head and all
有个光头的喇嘛
that, wearing and all that.
穿着这些衣服
Everybody was touching his feet, and the parents also
每个人都触摸他的双脚
not realized, my daughter is not realized, so she also
父母未有自觉，我的女儿也未有，所以她
touched his feet.
触摸他的双脚
She couldn’t bear it anymore now,
她不能再忍受
it was too much for her.
对她太过分了
She was sitting in a higher block, she went,
她坐在高处，她走去
put her hands back and looked at him, you see, told him.
把手放在后面，看着他，告诉他
She says, “What do you mean by asking everybody to
她说︰「你叫每个人
touch your feet? You’re not a even a realized soul.
触摸你的双脚是什么意思？你甚至不是个有自觉的灵
By wearing this dress of yours and shaving your head
穿着这样的衣服，光着头
you think you can ask people to touch your feet?”
你以为你可以要人触摸你的双脚？」
Little child of five years, yet she understands.
五岁的小孩子，但她明白这是什么一回事
We had once a program in India when they invited Me
在印度曾有一个讲座，他们邀请我
as a chief guest and for this Ramanmash?,
为主要的嘉宾，为此Ramanmash
she was a realized soul; and one gentleman from
她是个有自觉的灵，一个来自
Ramkrishna ashram from the head of that was sitting
Ramkrishna静室的男士
with his big orange robe, you see, sitting there.
穿着一件很大的橙色长袍坐在这里
And my, another granddaughter,
我的另一个外孙女
she was sitting in the front row.
她坐在前排
She couldn’t bear him anymore
她不能再忍受他
so she shouted from there,
所以她从这里大叫︰
“Mother, the one whose wearing a maxi dress,
母亲，那个穿着长裙的人
Grandmother, please ask him to get out,
祖母，请叫他走
he’s giving heat to all of us.”
他把热力带给所有人。」
So you see, there were many Sahaj Yogis who were
你要明白，很多霎哈嘉瑜伽士都
feeling the heat from this fellow and he thinks he’s a
感到热力来自这家伙，他以为自己
very spiritual man.
是很有灵性
She said, “Ask him to go, he’s wearing a maxi.”
她问︰「请他走，他穿着长裙。」
She didn’t understand it was a robe or thing.
她不懂这是长袍
Even children know
即使是孩子
who are realized souls and who are not,
若他们出生已有自觉，也能知道
if they are born realized.
谁是有自觉的灵，谁不是
There are many children who are born realized these days.
这些日子，很多孩子出生已有自觉
The time of judgment, this is the time of judgment.
审判的时刻，这是审判的时刻
Of course about this I’ll tell you later.
当然我会迟些才告诉你
Do You mind if I ask You a few questions?
男士︰你是否介意我问你一些问题？
It’s all right, I don’t mind.
不要紧，我不介意
But what happens, if you ask too many questions
但若你问太多问题
sometimes it becomes mental activity and may delay
有时会变成思维的活动，有时或许会
further Realization sometimes,
延误得到自觉
so I would advice you, if it is not so important, better
所以我建议你，若问题不重要
keep it out because, you see, answering the question is
最好还是不要问，因为回答问题
only on mental level.
只是在思维层次
I’m talking something much beyond, you see.
我说的是更为超越，你要明白
So, it is something logically if you have understood Me -
若你明白我，便知道这是合乎情理的
all right, let’s have it.
好吧，让我们有自觉
If it will work out, work out. If it will not work out,
若它能成就，便能成就，若不能
doesn’t matter.
不要紧
I’m here for three-four days, and we are going to work it
我会在这里三四天，我们会把它成就
out. All right?
好吧？
So it’s better to keep your mind at rest. Tell the mind,
最好还是保持头脑平静，告诉你的思维︰
“You have asked many questions before,
「你之前已经问了很多问题
you have thought of many things, now the time for you
想着很多事情，现在是时候
to receive the blessings of your own being.” All right?
你要接受你的存在体的祝福。」好吗？
If you tell your mind, it will rest.
若你告诉你的思维，它会安静下来
It’s a, it’s a wonderful thing mind is.
它是…思维是很奇妙的
If the mind knows what you want, and if it is the reality,
若你的思维知道你想要什么，若它是实相
it supports you and helps you very much.
它会支持你，帮助你
The same mind which can go astray, you see,
同样的思维若迷失了
it’s like sometimes I say it’s like a donkey,
就像我有时说它像一只驴子
like Christ used donkey just to suggest the mind
基督以驴子为例来解说思维
that if you allow it to go astray it will take you to all
若你容许它迷失，它便会
kinds of things, but if you control it, it takes you there
接受各种事物，若你控制它，它便能带你到
where you have to go.
你要到的地方
You just make him keep quiet.
你只要令它保持安静
It’s better to keep quiet at mind level.
最好思维保持安静
And that’s why I answered your questions because later
这就是我回答你的问题的原因，因为迟一点
on when the Kundalini’s rising, at that time,
当灵量升起，这时候
the mind should not stand up, isn’t it, to say that
思绪便不会浮现，是吗
“I haven’t asked this question.” That’s why.
不然思维会说︰「我没有问这个问题。」这就是原因
Just to soothe it – there’s no need –
只为安抚它，虽然没有必要
but, just to soothe it down, I do it. All right?
只为安抚它，我才这样做，对吗？
So best thing is to get your Realization is the best thing,
你最好还是得到自觉
otherwise this mind is quite a disturbing stuff.
不然这个思维是颇令人烦扰
It can come at the right time when you are going to
它会在合适的时间
achieve your last breakthrough, it may stop. All right?
你要最后突破时才浮现，它或许会停止，对吗？
So if you have any immediate question by which you are
若你有实时必须
really oppressed then you must ask Me.
发问的问题，请发问
But if it is not so important, just give up.
若问题并不重要，不要发问
Is it very important?
它是否很重要？
Then it’s all right. He has realized.
好吧，他已经知道